

FILIPE LEANDRO

• DETAILS •

João Pessoa Brazil +55 83 9 9184 1697 filipeleandro87@gmail.com

• SKILLS •

Nodejs

Python + Flask

Next.js + React

Serverless Architecture

Kubernetes

Docker

AWS Lambda + API Gateway

Microservices

Amazon Web Services

Java

IoT + MQTT

Web Sockets/Socket.io

Google Cloud/Firebase

Linux Administration

PostgreSQL, Oracle

Spring/Springboot

Raspberry & Electronics

Android & iOS

• LANGUAGES •

Portuguese

English

Spanish

• LINKS •

Linkedin

PROFILE

Started working as a Software Engineer developing Android and iOS apps for the R&D department of a Lisbon based consulting company while graduating in a MSc. in Distributed Systems and Software Engineering.

After graduating got a proposal to create the Android App for Hole 19 Golf, an award winner Startup focused on developing products for Golf players.

After Hole19, worked 4 years as a Software Architect in a Fintech company, Designing and Developing financial transactions systems with a very high transactional throughput, using Java, Spring and Oracle Database. Last project worked on was developing an Android SmartPOS with EMV Certified Transactions.

Founder at UNIO Smart Home, an IoT manufacturer for Smart Home devices. Developed the UNIO Cloud Platform using Python and Flask, deployed on a Serverless Architecture using AWS Lambda and API Gateway. Also developed the UNIO Server, a very low footprint application for Embedded Linux computers using Python, Flask and MQTT, deployed using Gunicorn and Supervisor. Co-designed all the hardware products and co-developed the Android and iOS apps.

Currently working as a Senior Software Engineer at Entando, designing and developing a Micro Frontend Platform on top of Kubernetes that helps companies create beautiful and scalable web applications. Currently Architecting and Developing an improved replacement for the platform key architectural component, the Web Renderization Engine, in Next.js and Single SPA and migrating reusable UI components into a framework agnostic architecture (Next.js, Vue, React, Angular, etc).

Certified AWS Solutions Architect - SAA-C02 May/2020

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer at Entando, Remote

July 2019 — Present

Working as a **Remote** Senior Software Engineer **Designing and Developing** a Micro Frontend Platform on top of Kubernetes that helps companies create beautiful and scalable web applications.

Helped migrate from a monolith Architecture into a more distributed approach by decoupling and developing core micro services using **Java**, **Spring Boot** and **Quarkus** and using **Keycloak** for cluster Identity and Access Management.

Currently **Architecting** and **Developing** an improved replacement for the platform key architectural component, the Web Renderization Engine, in **Next.js** and **Single SPA** and migrating reusable UI components into a **framework agnostic** architecture (Next.js, Vue, React, Angular, etc).

Founder at UNIO Smart Home, João Pessoa, Brazil

January 2017 — July 2019

Created UNIO Smart Home Cloud Platform (www.uniosmarthome.com) using Python and Flask, deployed on a Serverless Architecture using AWS Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB and Cognito.

Developed the UNIO Server for **Embedded Linux** environments using **Python**, **Flask** and **MQTT**, deployed using **Gunicorn** and **Supervisor** to monitor the unix process.

Co-designed all the hardware products and co-developed the Android app, using RxJava, Retrofit and Room, and the iOS app, using RxSwift, Moya and Realm. In both apps used the SocketIO Client to maintain a chat-like conversation with all the IoT devices.

Software Architect at Phoebus Tecnologia, João Pessoa, Brazil

March 2013 — January 2017

Worked as a Software Architect responsible for Designing and Developing financial transaction systems with a throughput of more than 1000/second EMV and PCI Compliant Transactions using **Java** and **Oracle Database**.

Worked on projects for major payment industry companies like Cielo, Rede and GetNet.

Led a team to develop an Android SmartPOS with **EMV Certified Transactions**. Also designed the PayStore Android Marketplace SDK for integration with third-party apps.

Lead Android Engineer Contract at R&D Agency, Lisbon, Portugal

October 2012 — March 2013

Worked on a contract for the R&D Agency (http://rd-agency.com) to develop an Android App for a major European Shopping Center Group (SonaeSierra) for users to access stores information and promotions, parking locations and indoor navigation maps using A* Graph Search Algorithm.

Android & iOS Engineer at Hole 19 Golf App & GPS, Lisbon, Portugal

September 2011 — September 2012

Joined the Hole19 Golf team (www.hole19golf.com) to develop the Android App, an award winner product focused on improving players performance with GPS navigation coordinates and statistical analysis.

Android & iOS Engineer at Beware, Lisbon, Portugal

 ${\sf September\,2010-September\,2011}$

Worked as a Junior Software Engineer developing Android and iOS apps for the R&D department of a Lisbon based consulting company.

EDUCATION

Masters in Distributed Systems and Software Engineering, Universidade Técnica de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal

September 2009 — September 2012

https://fenix.tecnico.ulisboa.pt/cursos/meic-a

Improved experience in Mobile Computation, Distributed Systems and Personal Information Systems.

Bachelor in Computer Science and Engineering, Universidade Técnica de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal

September 2005 — August 2009

https://fenix.tecnico.ulisboa.pt/cursos/leic-a

Improved experience with algorithms and development of mobile and web applications

COURSES

Certified AWS Solutions Architect SAA-C02, AWS

May 2020 — May 2022